# 这小球球可圆呼啊
How round is this little ball
# 又烫嘴又冰牙 冰火两重天
Both hot and icy in the same world
# 炸雪糕
Fried ice cream
# 一般的说 稍微有一点闪失
Normally if there are any mistake
# 这就会失败
It will fail
# 开始 最关键咱们是挂这个糊
Let’s get started, the key is to coat with the batter.
# 能挂得住
It has to stick on
# 一勺 玉米淀粉
One spoon of corn starch,
# 两勺 三勺
Two, three spoons.
# 然后这是吉士粉 一大勺 提香增色
Then another large spoon of custard powder to bring up the colour and flavour
# 这是面粉 标准粉 九勺
This is all purpose flour, nine spoons
# 四五六七八九
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 (counting)
# 加水 常温的水
Add water, room temperature water.
# 这个糊这叫什么 脆皮糊
What do you call this batter? Crispy crust batter
# 你看这水他一点一点的稀释
Look, he slowly adds water to the mixture
# 这样子我们网友就好学
This way you guys can learn it easier
# 一点一点的兑水一点点弄
Adding water and mixing bit by bit
# 你看看你看隋坡调这糊 很柔
Look how smooth Sui Po has made this batter to be
# 他一点点调 他不是说使劲打
He does it bit by bit and not beating (the batter) very hard.
# 他不让它上劲儿
This way it won’t form glutens
# 还有一个手法
There’s another technique
# 你不能顺着一个方向使劲抽
You can’t whisk hard in the same direction
# 抽上劲儿了它就完了
You are failed once you’ve formed glutens
# 你看当中还有一些面粉颗粒
You can see there are some lumps of flour in the mix
# 稀释还不是很完全 没关系稍微放一下
It’s not completely combined with water, it’s ok let’s set it aside for a while
# 我们（放）泡打粉  稍微沉淀一下
Let’s add baking powder and let it sit for a while
# 泡打粉看看拿来了
Baking powder is here
# 一小平勺差不多五克
One spoon is about 5 grams
# 泡打粉起起的作用
Baking powder act as the riser
# 加油 这是有十克的油
Add oil, here is about 10 grams of oil
# 调到滋润了均匀了没有颗粒状
Mix until it’s consistent and no lumps
# 然后加油 油它是起酥的作用
Then add oil, oil adds crispiness to the batter
# 这油要打进去吗 打进去
Do we whisk the oil in to the mix? Yes we do
# 网友看着啊 这油要打进去
Look guys, we need to whisk the oil into the mix.
# 打进去还得融合在一起
Not only that, it needs to bind with the mix
# 表面不能看出浮油来
No visible oil on the surface
# 这个打到最后还要放置五分钟十分钟
Then set it aside for 5 to 10 min
# 让它醒发一下 泡打粉要起作用
Let it rise and for the baking powder to do its job
# 还有油它跟面粉跟淀粉融合之后
And oil and flour mixed with starch
# 就像打完了稀奶油似的
It looks like whipped cream once done
# 那种感觉比较细腻
You get those smooth texture
# 炸什么都好吃这个糊
It makes everything delicious once coated with this
# 炸个香蕉苹果的 葡萄西瓜都能用
Goes well with bananas, apples, grapes and watermelons.
# 炸虾都行
Even with shrimps
# 这个攉拢到什么程度 拉起来
What state do we want this mix to be, when you draw it up
# 成一条线
It forms a line
# 烧油 坐上油锅了啊
Heat up the oil, put the wok on the stove.
# 这是巧克力 巧克力雪糕
This is chocolate, chocolate (coated) ice cream
# 拿牙签给它插上 这有点意思
Poke a few toothpick on it, this is interesting.
# 一百七十度 一百七十多了
170 degree Celsius, over 170
# 稀了不行 稠了不行
Not too thin nor too thick.
# 不起还不行 火候还得注意呢
Also won’t work if the oil temperature is not high enough, have to keep an eye on the temperature
# 挂的糊多了就起的特别大
It puffs too big if the coating is too thick.
# 然后进去就完蛋了
Then you are screwed
# 糊少了 不起
It won’t puff up if the coating is too thin
# 好了 下锅吧
Alright let’s drop them in
# 起来了
There is puffs up
# 没问题
No problems
# 好了这不能再炸了 再炸就化了
Ok don’t fry any longer otherwise it will melt
# 看啊网友们 这东西炸出来就赶快吃
Look friends, quickly put them in your mouth once it came out (P.S Not recommended if over 40 degree Celsius)
# 外边很焦脆 里边似化非化 还带点小冰碴
The outer crust is crispy and the inside is half melted with some ice inside
# 二伯这是你的了
This is yours, Er Bai
# 化了么 有点硬心儿么
Is it melted? Does it have a bit of hard inside?
# 这壳酥酥的 但是酥而不艮
The coat is crispy yet not hard to chew
# 这炸的比您那炸的好
This is better than yours
# 有人想吃了 就进来了
Someone wanted to eat then they came
# 来啊 来人
Come, come everybody
# 小焦赶紧尝尝
Xiao Jiao have a taste
# 抓点紧 一会化了
Hurry, before it melts
# 这一绝 真好吃这个
Amazing, this is great
# 这要是说 第一口让你逮着了
You’ve got the first bite of it
# 学一学 吉士粉淀粉面粉
Learn this, custard powder, starch and plain flour
# 好产品对我们来讲是吸引啊
Good product is an attraction to us.
# 有吸引力
Very Attractive indeed
# 现代化产品 一百八十度
Modern product. 180 degrees
# 看见没有 热了再加点
Look, add a bit (of oil) after it’s too hot
# 因为什么比一百八十度稍微有点高了
Because it’s over 180 degrees
# 要回到一百八十度
Cool it down, back to 180 degrees
# 亮子 准备 拿盘儿
Liang Zi, get ready, bring a plate
# 让它里边有点生的好吃
It tastes better with some hard ice cream on the inside
# 有点似化非化的
It’s half melted
# 我给你照着
Let me film this for you
# 这个好玩又好吃 第一个让我吃了
This is both fun and delicious, I had the first one
# 冰凉
Icy cold
# 冰火两重天 又烫嘴又冰牙
The mouth feeling is both hot and cold, it’s an interesting mix-up feeling in the mouth.
# 你看这就是火候
You see this is Huo Hou (The control on temperate and time)
# 外边是烫嘴 里边是冰牙
It’s hot on the outside while cold inside
# 我再来一个
Let me have another one
# 好快 亮子
You are moving fast! Liang Zi
# 这小球球可圆呼啊 再蘸点玫瑰酱
This little ball is very round, dip it in some rose jam
# 最关键是什么 这里边还没化
The key is to keep the inside unmelted
# 冻着呢 这就是火候掌握的准确
It is, that’s how accurate the temperature and time is controlled
# shift forward 00:04:51,100
# 悄悄的胡说八道您还记得吧
Do you still remember 'Let’s gossip behind his back‘ (a online friend)?
# 我知道
I know
# 她那天留言说无情铁手再现江湖
She replied that the emotionless iron hand has just back in town
# 说直接从油里把酥肉拿出来
Saying that you pick the crispy meat straight out of the boiling oil with your bare hand
# 就喂刚强吃
Then fed Gang Qiang
# 就好多网友都想问您
Many friends wanted to ask you that
# 就我们小时候玩
Back in the old days when we were little,
# 最早小魏知道 烧那个煤球
Wei knows that the coal balls
# 那时候没有现在这环境 什么煤气啊
Unlike nowadays we have natural gas and everything
# 那时候小孩不懂事啊
Kids at that age knew nothing
# 然后说夹煤球
Then trying to pick out coal balls (from the stove)
# 谁把煤球拿出来给谁多少钱
Whoever get the coal ball out got some money
# 那净是不要命的
That’s nuts
# 直接下手了
Straightly use bare hands
# 直接拿手拿起来了
Picked up with bare hands
# 其实就给这五毛钱
Then the reward was only 50 cents
# 那手全烫焦了
The hand was completely burnt
# 练出来了
You’ve gained a skill
# 哎 就这么着
Yep just like that
# 久而久之 铁手就练成了
Then my hands become iron hands just like that over time.
# 然后再加上长期工作 油啊
Besides, working in the kitchen and dealing with oil for so many years
# 包括像咱们现在炒菜
When we’re cooking nowadays
# 碰上点热油根本就不当回事了
We don’t even care if some hot oil spills on us
# 就过去哎呦 有这种反应
But we used to react when it happened
# 现在就是 疼一下就疼一下了
But now we are like, whatever
# 咱们手上也是
Also on our hands
# 基本上都是
It’s basically
# 看我这个都是烫的
Look at mine,
# 这都是烫的
It’s all from hot oil
# 这是刀伤
And this is from knife
```